# 哈喽大家好
Hello, everyone!
# 这个我们昨天剩的两条鱼今天我们把它烤了
We are going to grill these two fish left from yesterday.
# 做烤鱼 炭火烤鱼
We'll grill them, with charcoal.
# 可以啊
Sure.
# 我今天炭已经生好了
I've lit up the charcoal.
# 正好以前用的那个炉子放了很久也要用一下
And we'll use that stove, which has been left idle for a long time.
# 我们一般做烤鱼都是从背上开
We normally cut fish open from the dorsal side when grilling.
# 今下午你又干饱餐
You cheeky roster coming for a feast again.
# 倒了这个水
I'll empty the pot.
# 烤鱼改刀就随便有几刀就可以了
It's enough to just cut several times on the fish skin.
# 2条鱼都放得下
It's large enough for two fish.
# 还可以哦 刚好
Perfect.
# 嘿 安逸得很
Ha! It's nice and tight.
# 我们用这个架子把它夹起来烤
We'll use this frame to grill.
# 先放旁边 先弄配料
Now set it aside. Let's prepare the ingredients first.
# 这个烤鱼你们想吃什么都可以放进去
You can put anything you like into the dish.
# 洋葱基本上是用来垫底
Onions are normally for the base.
# 垫底的话也可以用豆芽
Bean sprouts are also a good choice.
# 大蒜切一刀都可以了
Cutting garlic in half is enough.
# 好 少放点嘛
Let's not add too much (dried chili peppers).
# 少放点
Indeed.
# 你还是有喊辣的时候啊
Sometimes it's even too spicy for you, isn't it uncle?
# 那肯定的哦
Of course.
# 加点花椒
Add some Sichuan peppercorns.
# 花椒你到是吃得哦
You can have some Sichuan peppercorns, right?
# 那个嚼来吃都可以
I can eat them dry.
# 那样子多放点
Then let's have some more.
# 可以啊
For sure.
# 这是你上次没吃完的火锅底料
This is the hotpot soup base left from last time.
# 可以弄点在里面噶
You can add some in.
# 这是我们自己做的火锅底料
This is the soup base we made,
# 我的配方做的
based on my own formula.
# 一半都怕多了哦
Half of it is too much, isn't it?
# 2条（鱼）都嘛还有那么多配菜 是不是
But we have 2 fish and many other ingredients, right?
# 闻到真的多香
It smells so good!
# 你想吃香菜等会儿可以加点香菜进去
You can add some coriander later if you want.
# 好 差不多了
Ok. Preparation done!
# 现在先考鱼嘛
Let's grill the fish now.
# 烤嘛烤嘛 把火点起
Sure. Light up the fire.
# 可以了 现在我们这个炭已经夹上来了
Good. We've brought up the charcoal.
# 现在火力还比较大
And the heat is strong.
# 我给你们分享一下
Let me tell you:
# 你一般在外面馆子里面吃烤鱼
If you go to a restaurant ordering grilled fish,
# 凡是是20分钟以内上的鱼
and the fish is served within 20 minutes,
# 都不是炭烤的 全是油炸的
it is definitely fried and not grilled.
# 我们这个烤鱼必须烤够40分钟
Fish needs to be grilled for at least 40 minutes
# 才能够把这个鱼烤干烤焦烤香
to become dry, crispy and in a good flavor.
# 咦 你看
Ei, see?
# 还在动
It's still moving.
# 嘿嘿嘿 还安逸
Hehehe, good!
# 还在闪（抖）
Still moving.
# 我们这个烤鱼一开始要大火烤猛火烤
We should start with strong heat,
# 把它的水份短时间内烤干
to dry the fish in a short time.
# 然后两面烤干了之后
Then when both sides are dry,
# 再把炭火剥掉一些再小火慢慢的烤
remove some charcoal and use low heat to cook.
# 咿呀 好烫噢
Ya. It's hot.
# 刚刚火力太大了我去了一些炭
The heat was too strong earlier and I've removed some charcoal.
# 现在只留了几块炭在这里
Now only a few is left.
# 现在都有点金黄金黄的了
The fish is turning golden.
# 现在我们这个烤鱼已经烤了半个小时了
We are half a hour in cooking the fish.
# 大家可以看一下现在这个
You can see that,
# 已经金黄金黄的了但是还是不够
the fish is indeed golden but not good enough yet.
# 烤来好吃下次我把我那只大公鸡杀来烤
If this gilled fish is delicious, I'll catch that roster and grill it.
# 大公鸡杀来烤了好吃我又杀鸭子来烤
If grilled roster also turns out good, I'll try on ducks next.
# 好了 你看我们的这个鱼
Good. Look at those fish.
# 已经烤得可以了
They are good enough.
# 它的皮已经脆了你看这里它的尾巴
The skin is crispy and the tail
# 尾巴就是捏一下就可以全部糟了碎了
crumbles to squeeze.
# 这个烤鱼的话才是烤到了位
Now the fish is perfectly grilled.
# 现在这个时候来刷点油
Let's brush some oil next.
# 刷油的话就是方便它粘上辣椒面孜然粉之类的
Oil helps chili powder and cumin seed powder to stick.
# 现在给它刷一下油
Now, brush some oil.
# 翻过来再刷一下
And do the same on the other side.
# 哦 中间燃了
Oh, it's burning in the middle.
# 这个油刷好了再放点这个孜然粉
Spary some cumin seed powder when oiled.
# 撒孜然
Now, spray some cumin seed powder,
# 油已经OK了
as the oil is OK.
# 在撒点辣椒面
Now, add some chili pepper powder.
# 加不加花椒 四伯爷
You want some Sichuan peppercorns, uncle?
# 要 咋子不加花椒呢
Of course. Add some.
# 花椒加起那个味道才安逸
No peppercorns means no flavor.
# 好 差不多了
Good! Almost done.
# 一 二 三
One, two, three.
# 嘿嘿 差一点翻在地上去了
Hehe, almost drop the fish.
# 不可能
Rest assured.
# 听这个声音就能感觉到这个已经脆了
The fish is crispy judging by the sound of it.
# 它要贴在上面是很正常的
It's normal to stick on the frame.
# 因为这个鱼皮（已经烤焦了）
Because the skin (is burned).
# 好 现在来炒这个
Good. Now let's cook the other ingredients.
# 这个油我随便放点哈
Add some oil.
# 好了好了差不多了
Alas! It's enough.
# 现在我们来炒这个料
Now let's cook the seasoning ingredients.
# 当然烤鱼的话鱼越大这个油越多
Bigger fish needs more oil (to cook).
# 其实这点油我觉得少了一点
I kind of feel like we need more oil.
# 2个鱼好多点嘛
We only have two fish.
# 够了
It should be good.
# 烤鱼就是油要多一点
It's normally a lot of oil when cooking fish.
# 这个就要慢慢爆
Let it cook slowly.
# 让它把这个料头爆香
And wait until the flavor comes out.
# 到时候再放这个火锅底料
Then it's time to put in this hotpot soup base.
# 它这个大蒜起泡了就说明这个蒜油已经出来了
When those garlic form bubbles, it means we've extracted the garlic oil.
# 可以了
It's good enough.
# 这个等它慢慢炒
We'll wait for it to cook.
# 我们把这个炒化了加一点点水
When (the soup base) melts, add a little bit of water.
# 如果有啤酒的就可以加一点啤酒
If you have beer, you can also add that instead.
# 给它煮化调盐白糖啊这些味给它一调
When (the soup base) fully dissolved, season with salt, cane sugar, etc.
# 调好之后再倒在哪个烤鱼盘里面
Then after seasoning, pour the soup into a square pan.
# 最后放在这个炭火上面慢慢烤
Put the pan on the grill and slow cook.
# 慢慢加热慢慢吃
Eat hot while it's slowly cooked.
# 吃完鱼之后可以加一点自己喜欢的菜
After finishing the fish, you can add other ingredients you like.
# 现在我们这个火锅底料已经炒香炒化了
Now the soup base is melted.
# 加点这个水
Let's add some water.
# 这水不能加太多 加太多了就不香了
Don't add too much or it'll make the soup bland.
# 好 这个加了水之后开始调味
Start seasoning after adding some water.
# 盐的话就一定要控制它的量不能太多
Restrain from adding too much salt.
# 好 盐就是这么多大概的话3克左右
Good. 3 grams are about enough.
# 然后再加这个白糖
Then add some cane sugar.
# 白糖大概是盐的两倍
Put in twice as much sugar as salt.
# 然后少加点鸡精
Then add some broth powder.
# 大概1勺也是3克吧
About one spoonful, 3 grams.
# 然后把这个土豆跟香菇丢下去煮一下
Then boil those potato and mushroom.
# 现在我们这个汤汁已经熬好了
Now the soup is ready.
# 咸不咸
Is it salty?
# 不咸吧 刚好合适
Not too much salt? Just right?
# 合适
Just right.
# 等一下我们把这个烤鱼盘放在上面把这个汤汁倒进去就可以了
We'll put the pan up here and pour the soup in the pan in a little bit.
# 哎呀 好辣哦
Ayo, it's spicy.
# 辣吗
How spicy?
# 很辣很辣
Super spicy.
# 我们这个下面是放的炭
We have some charcoal underneath.
# 所以这个就刚刚好这样子放进去
So it's perfect to just put the pan here.
# 放进去了之后放洋葱
Then add some onion.
# 洋葱撒再这个上面
Just lay around the fish.
# 现在这个汤已经差不多了
Now the soup is ready.
# 我把这个汤淋上去
I'll pour the soup on top of the fish.
# 这个时候呢我们就撒这个葱段
Now it's time to add some cut green onions,
# 然后把我们这个魔芋 魔芋是焯过水的
and this parboiled knojac jelly.
# 边吃边加
And we'll add some more when we eat.
# 边吃边加进去
Add while we eat.
# 再把这个蒜苗撒在上面去
Then put some garlic sprouts on top.
# 还有这个鱼腥草
And some fish mint.
# 我们四川人喜欢吃鱼腥草嘛
Our Sichuanese people like fish mint.
# 撒点鱼香草在这个上面
Now, add some fish mint.
# 好 剩下的就交给时间把它慢慢煮开
Good. Now we wait for it to boil.
# 味道很好吃
It's really good,
# 特别是这个鱼啊特别的香
especially the fish which is really well-flavored.
# 这个土豆可能很好吃
This potato looks good.
# 土豆你尝一下嘛
Try it.
# 这魔芋呀这些东西要煮一下
Konjac jelly and other ingredients need to be boiled first.
# 这土豆是脆的
It's crisp.
# 好吃噶 嗯
- Does it tastes good? - Yes.
# 这个跟烤牛腿那个好吃哦
Compared to roasted beef leg, which one is better?
# 这个好吃点
This one.
# 这个好吃 嗯
- This one is better. - Yes.
# 这个还便宜点
This is actually cheaper to make than beef leg.
# 这个吃起来味道都要安逸点
This suits my taste.
# 味道有一点点重
I think it's a little bit over-seasoned.
# 太辣了
It looks spicy.
# 不重啊
I think it's fine.
# 辣味有一点点重
I think it's a little too spicy.
# 嗯 好吃
Uhm, it's delicious.
# 辣味要少一点
It should be less spicy.
# 咿呀 好辣哦
Yiya. Too spicy!
# 吃还是好吃 吃魔芋
Anyway, it tastes good. Let me try some konjac jelly.
# 你们可以在家里面试一下
You can try cooking this dish at home.
# 这个鱼非常的入味非常好吃
The fish is well-cooked and very delicious.
# 很简单就用火锅底料
It's also easy to make with some hotpot soup base.
# 加点调料料头把它爆香了加水煮
Cook the minor ingredients to bring out the flavor and then boil.
# 这个鱼皮才好吃
The fish skin is the best.
# 嗯
Yes.
# 鱼皮煮起很好吃
Boiled fish skin is indeed good.
# 这个皮子好吃的很
This fish skin is really good.
# 好啦 本期视频就到这里了
Alright, that's all for this episode.
# 我们要慢慢吃了
We are going to enjoy this grilled fish.